Sandra García

Nationality Spanish

Contact Details Email: sandra.garcia@insead.edu Mobile: +34 646 69 35 69

SUMMARY

Case Team Leader at Bain & Company with more than 6 years of experience as Management Consultant and M&A/Private Equity Lawyer. Experience across industries with focus on Private Equity, Consumer Products and Retail and across geographies both in developed and emerging markets (Europe, South East Asia and India). MBA from INSEAD and LLM from IE Law School.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2015 -Bain & Company Top tier management consulting firm **Europe / South East Asia**

Present

Case Team Leader, Private Equity, Consumer Products & Retail Practice Groups

Private Equity Practice

- Advised private equity funds on commercial due diligences across sectors (e-commerce and corporate services) and geographies (Europe and South East Asia)
- Analyzed market trends and competitive position in the context of commercial due diligences; assessed and modelled market projections and target's top line and bottom line upside potential

Corporate Projects

- Designed the growth strategy for leading consumer products companies; identified and modelled the impact of growth initiatives within different brands/products
- Performed store revenue and profitability analysis across >1000 outlets for the retail business of leading South East Asian oil & gas company; optimized store distribution and dealer terms (full potential +70% store revenue)
- Advised major r

creation

Led workshops with >30 executives to prioritize growth initiatives for major companies

2009 -13

UK / Spain

Freshfields Bruckhaus Deringer LLP Top tier international law firm

2014 (summer)

Present

Aditya Birla Retail (Intern) Retail business of the second largest Indian conglomerate

India

- Developed a market opportunity assessment and screening of potential businesses; identified two fast-growing opportunities (8% and 16% revenue growth)
- Developed the business plan and go-to-market strategy and defined the implementation across regions

EDUCATION

2014 INSEAD MBA Class of December 2014 Singapore / France 2008 -09 IE Law School LLM Corporate Business Law. Graduated with Distinction - top 5% **Spain** Universidad de Oviedo/Helsinki University Bachelor of Laws - top 5% Spain / Finland 2003 -08

LANGUAGES Spanish (Native), English (Fluent), French (Business)

OTHER EXPERIENCE

2012 -Fundación Recover (Volunteer) NGO focused on improving the health system in Africa

Cameroon / Spain

- Conducted several projects aimed at improving the profitability of hospitals in Cameroon
- Led different fundraising initiatives aimed at providing medical equipment for hospitals in Africa
- Freshfields Pro-Bono Group (Social Impact & Pro Bono) 2009 -13

UK / Spain

Member of the Pro Bono Group advising leading non-profit organizations and charities on corporate and financial matters; Advised The Global Fund to fight AIDS, Tuberculosis and Malaria in Ecuador on the development of the Debt2Health Initiative